Guest

Keywords  

[Login](https://www.nintendolife.com/login) or [Sign Up](https://www.nintendolife.com/register)

Navigation: [Home](https://www.nintendolife.com/ "Home") / [Terms of Use](https://www.nintendolife.com/terms "Terms of Use") / Privacy Policy

======================================================

This privacy policy sets out how Nintendo Life uses and protects any information that you give us when you use this website.

On this page: [Privacy Policy](https://www.nintendolife.com/privacy)

1. 1.[Data we collect](https://www.nintendolife.com/privacy#data-we-collect)
2. 2.[What we do with the data we gather](https://www.nintendolife.com/privacy#what-we-do-with-the-data-we-gather)
3. 3.[Security](https://www.nintendolife.com/privacy#security)
4. 4.[How we use cookies](https://www.nintendolife.com/privacy#how-we-use-cookies)
    1. 4.1.[Third-Party Advertising and Content Services](https://www.nintendolife.com/privacy#third-party-advertising-and-content-services)
5. 5.[Links to other websites](https://www.nintendolife.com/privacy#links-to-other-websites)
6. 6.[Controlling your personal information](https://www.nintendolife.com/privacy#controlling-your-personal-information)
7. 7.[Removing your data](https://www.nintendolife.com/privacy#removing-your-data)
8. 8.[Poll & Survey Data](https://www.nintendolife.com/privacy#poll-andamp-survey-data)
9. 9.[Competition Entries](https://www.nintendolife.com/privacy#competition-entries)
10. 10.[How to contact us](https://www.nintendolife.com/privacy#how-to-contact-us)

We are committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

We may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from 27th Aug, 2024.

Data we collect
---------------

If you decide to create an account and login, we collect the following information:

* username & password (required)
* email address & email preferences (required)
* country / timezone (required)
* ip address & user agent (required)
* profile description / forum signature (optional)
* social media account information (optional)
* gamer IDs (eg, PSN ID, Nintendo Network ID etc) (optional)
* demographic information such as interests (optional)
* answers to polls, surveys and questionnaire (optional)
* game ratings (optional)
* comments, posts and forum topics (optional)
* liked comments/posts/articles (optional)

What we do with the data we gather
----------------------------------

We use this data to understand your needs as a user and provide you with a better, personalised service, and in particular for the following reasons:

* We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests or location.
* We may use the information to improve our products and services.
* We may periodically send promotional emails about new content, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided, if you have opted into receive them.

Security
--------

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the data we collect.

How we use cookies
------------------

Cookies are small bits of data stored by your device which are sent back to our server whenever you view a page, typically it’s an identifier so we know who is viewing the page and can display user-specific information such as your username or perform an action on your behalf such as posting a comment.

Without cookies we wouldn’t be able to identify your account and you wouldn’t be able to interact with the page. Different cookies are used for different purposes, often they are purely functional or performance based, for example, so we can see how many unique users are visiting the website. Cookies can also be used to provide targeted advertisements, or tailored advertising based on sites you’ve visited before.

We respect your privacy therefore you can choose not to allow some types of cookies. However, blocking some types of cookies may impact your experience of the site and the services we are able to offer.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. You can choose your cookie settings at any time using the following dialog:

### Third-Party Advertising and Content Services

ReedPop/Gamer Network provide the advertising infrastructure on this website. They use third-party advertising and content services, particularly within our marketing or free content sites, for the purposes of analysing visitor / customer site interactions including interactions with our online marketing campaigns, attribution purposes to link ecommerce purchases to our brand, and advertising. For more information including how to opt-out, please see below:

| Third-Party Provider | Description |
| --- | --- |
| [Google Ads](https://safety.google/intl/en_uk/privacy/ads-and-data/)<br><br>[Google Ad-Tech Vendors](https://developers.google.com/third-party-ads/adx-vendors)<br><br>[Opt-out](https://adssettings.google.co.uk/anonymous?sig=ACi0TChEO5iHkoMUFwUGa-VsoApZr4GInC7JE1pmukczhQi13EHQsFfuSK8eXqtBGQYFRNZ5JQJwt5gzfA9kSGSkZvTa-t8tFIbKAKZuGdHCkkRI1RjqPxc&hl=en) | Google Ads is an online advertising platform that we use to promote our events, online content and services on Google Search, YouTube, and other sites across the web. Google Ads is also used by some advertisers to buy adverts that appear on our Sites. |
| [Google Analytics](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-US)<br><br>[Opt-out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) | We use Google Analytics to provide site visitor measurements and statistics as well as personalised advertising. |
| [YouTube API](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy)<br><br>[Opt-out](https://security.google.com/settings/security/permissions) | YouTube’s API services are used to help us deliver content, visitor measurements, statistics and advertising revenues. |

Alternatively, you may opt-out of third-party web advertising services via the opt-out tools listed below:

Please note: Clicking the links above will redirect you to the appropriate third party website. We are not responsible for the content of external websites.

You can also configure your web browser to delete and / or block the use of cookies for any third party.

Opting out of advertising cookies will not remove advertising from the pages you visit; instead it means the ads you will see may not be matched to your interests.

Links to other websites
-----------------------

Our website will contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

Controlling your personal information
-------------------------------------

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:

* Don't enter information you do not wish to share with us
* Whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes
* If you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for newsletter purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or emailing us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.nintendolife.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or by updating your account preferences.

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your explicit permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998 / General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) (EU) 2016/679. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to Hookshot Media Ltd, 5 Oakwood Drive, Loughborough, Leicestershire, LE11 3QF, United Kingdom or email us [\[email protected\]](https://www.nintendolife.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

Removing your data
------------------

If you wish to delete your account, simply visit the account page (whilst logged in), click 'Delete Account' and follow the instructions. Your account, and all the data related to your account, will be deleted from our website within 24 hours. Your residual data may exist within our backup systems for up to 14 days.

Poll & Survey Data
------------------

When we publish polls and surveys you are invited to submit your answers to our servers and is entirely voluntary. Your responses will be stored in our secure database. Often our poll/survey results are published instantly but in an aggregated and anonymised form. Sometimes we share these aggregated and anonymised results (sometimes segmented/cross-referenced by other responses you have made) with third parties, however, your individual responses will not be given to any third party whatsoever.

Competition Entries
-------------------

Winners may be requested to take part in post competition promotional activity and we reserve the right to use the username, names and location (country) of winners, their photographs and audio and/or visual recordings of them in any publicity unless you specify otherwise.

Data relating to competition entrants will be retained for a reasonable period after the competition closes to assist us to operate competitions in a consistent manner and to deal with any queries. Data will then be removed from our systems and will not be used for marketing.

On the occasion that a third party, such as the product supplier, advertising agency or PR company who sponsor that competition is to provide prize(s) directly, your contact details and, if applicable mailing address, will be passed to the third party for the sole reason of delivering the prize.

How to contact us
-----------------

If you have any questions or concerns about our policy, please contact us by filling in our online [contact](https://www.nintendolife.com/contact) form.

_Last Updated: August, 2024_

Popular Right Now

* [Dbrand Seems To Have Shared Images Of Switch 2 Inside Its New CaseYesterday, 8:10pm](https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2024/12/dbrand-seems-to-have-shared-images-of-switch-2-inside-its-new-case)
* ['Hyperdimension Neptunia' & 'Death End' Switch Releases Scrapped For "Not Complying With Nintendo Guidelines"Yesterday, 5:30pm](https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2024/12/hyperdimension-neptunia-and-death-end-switch-releases-scrapped-for-not-complying-with-nintendo-guidelines)
* [Black Friday 2024: Best Deals On Nintendo Switch Consoles, Games, eShop Credit, Accessories And MoreMon 2nd Dec 2024](https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/black-friday-2024-best-deals-on-nintendo-switch-consoles-games-eshop-credit-accessories-and-more)
* [Best Retro Throwback Nintendo Switch Games - Modern Games With Old-School StyleTue 3rd Dec 2024](https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/best-retro-throwback-nintendo-switch-games-modern-games-with-old-school-style)
* [Bandai Namco Unveils New Pac-Man Game, And It's Probably Not What You ExpectYesterday, 12:55am](https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2024/12/bandai-namco-unveils-new-pac-man-game-and-its-probably-not-what-you-expect)
* [Nintendo Shares Special Message: "Thank You For Joining Us Now And Into The Future"Yesterday, 6:05am](https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2024/12/nintendo-shares-special-message-thank-you-for-joining-us-now-and-into-the-future)
* [Random: PlayStation's Astro Bot Director Pays Tribute To Mario And Nintendo In GOTY SpeechYesterday, 5:15am](https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2024/12/random-playstations-astro-bot-director-pays-tribute-to-mario-and-nintendo-in-goty-speech)
* [Best Nintendo Christmas Gifts 2024: Switch Games, eShop Credit And Lots More!Wed, 2pm](https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/best-nintendo-christmas-gifts-2024-switch-games-eshop-credit-and-lots-more)
* [Reaction: The Game Awards Left Us With One Big Question: Will Any Of This Run On Switch 2?Yesterday, 1:05pm](https://www.nintendolife.com/features/reaction-the-game-awards-left-us-with-one-big-question-will-any-of-this-run-on-switch-2)
* [Pac-Man's New Game 'Shadow Labyrinth' Is Getting A Physical Switch Release4:05am](https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2024/12/pac-mans-new-game-shadow-labyrinth-is-getting-a-physical-switch-release)
* [3D Print Of Rumoured 'Switch 2' Design Gives Us A Closer Look At OLED Size ComparisonWed, 7pm](https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2024/12/3d-print-of-rumoured-switch-2-design-gives-us-a-closer-look-at-oled-size-comparison)

Join **1,464,732** people following **Nintendo Life**:

© 2024 [Hookshot Media](https://hookshot.media/), partner of [IGN Entertainment](https://www.ziffdavis.com/brands/entertainment) | Hosted by [44 Bytes](https://www.44bytes.net/) | [ AdChoices](https://www.nintendolife.com/privacy) | [Do Not Sell My Personal Information](https://dsar.ziffdavis.com/)

* Friends:

All the latest Nintendo goodness straight to your inbox
